Guide to the John Farquhar Fulton Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Special Subjects, 1892-1965; Series II
  Two sets of files document Fulton's contributions to both government and civilian programs during World War II. The National Research Council (NRC) files focus on the Committee on Aviation Medicine and Fulton's chairmanship of the Subcommittee on Decompression Sickness and of the Subcommittee on Historical Records. The NRC files contain minutes, agendas, reports, conference notes, and letters to and from members of the committees as well as with friends and NRC administrators. The Subcommittee on Historical Records files detail Fulton's commitment to publishing a multi-volume medical history of World War II, and the files contain volume outlines, assignments, and correspondence with authors. Correspondence with government officials traces the project through to its eventual demise. The files "Yale Faculty Committee for Receiving Oxford and Cambridge University Children, Inc." document arrangements by which Yale faculty brought British children to New Haven to care for them during the bombing attacks on Great Britain. The files contain correspondence with British parents, host faculty members, and committees at other universities.
  Fulton's scientific research and teaching at Yale took place in the Laboratory of Physiology. The Laboratory of Physiology files document administrative aspects of some research projects, including lobotomy experiments and government-sponsored investigations in the field of aero-space medicine. There are no research notebooks, and teaching materials are limited to course outlines. A listing of fellows who worked in the Laboratory is included (folder 885). Fulton's expedition to collect and subsequent efforts to import and breed lemurs and Tarsius monkeys as experimental subjects are described in the section "Tarsius monkeys."
  Files under several headings concern Fulton's editorial work. Correspondence under "Association for Research in Nervous and Mental Diseases" reveals his leadership during his two terms as the president in planning two annual meetings and publishing the resulting volumes: Volume 27, Frontal Lobes, in 1939 and Volume 20, Hypothalmus, in 1947. In recognition of his skills as an editor, Fulton was invited to revise two classic medical texts: Garrison's Textbook of Physiology and Howell's Introduction to Medical History. The folders under each title contain drafts, background materials, notes, correspondence with the publishers, and, in the case of the Howell book, exchanges with contributors. Fulton was founder and editor of the serial, Journal of Physiology. These files include correspondence concerning manuscripts submitted for publication and "top sheets" containing reviews of the manuscripts.
  - Army Medical Library
    - General
      - 1927-1949 (Box 195, Folder 1-8)
      - 1950-1953, 1956 (Box 196, Folder 9-10)
    - Association of Honorary Consultants
      - First Annual Meeting, 1944 (Box 196, Folder 11)
      - Second Annual Meeting, 1945 (Box 196, Folder 12)
      - Third Annual Meeting, 1946 (Box 196, Folder 13)
      - Fourth Annual Meeting, 1947 (Box 196, Folder 14)
        See also: Series VI, box 319, folder 2
      - Fifth Annual Meeting, 1948 (Box 196, Folder 15)
      - Sixth-Eighth Annual Meeting, 1949-1951 (Box 196, Folder 16)
      - Acquisitions committee, 1945-1947 (Box 196, Folder 17)
      - Committee of consultants for the study of the indices to medical literature (Box 196, Folder 18)
        - 1947-1949 (Box 196, Folder 19)
        - 1950-1952 (Box 197, Folder 20)
      - Executive committee, 1944-1947 (Box 197, Folder 21-24)
    - Cataloging classifications, 1944 (Box 197, Folder 25)
    - Cleveland branch, 1944-1948 (Box 197, Folder 26)
    - Constitution and by-laws, undated (Box 197, Folder 27)
    - Incunabula catalogue
      - General correspondence, 1947-1950 (Box 197, Folder 28)
      - Subscriptions and contributions, 1949-1950 (Box 197, Folder 29)
    - Survey, 1944 (Box 197, Folder 30)
  - Association for Research in Nervous and Mental Diseases
    - General, 1934-1954 (Box 198, Folder 31-35)
    - Frontal Lobes v. 27 [correspondence A-Z], 1947-1948 (Box 198, Folder 36-41)
    - Hypothalmus v. 20
      - Correspondence
        - A-S, 1938-1940 (Box 199, Folder 42-49)
        - U-Z, 1938-1940 (Box 200, Folder 50-52)
  - Bibliophilia
    - Banned (burned) books, 1941-1944 (Box 200, Folder 53)
    - Book collections, personal, undated (Box 200, Folder 54)
    - Book dealers
      - A (Box 200, Folder 55)
      - A. Maltby and Son, 1924-1940 (Box 200, Folder 56-57)
      - Andrew, Warland, 1929-1931 (Box 200, Folder 58)
      - Argosy Book Stores, 1931-1940, 1953 (Box 200, Folder 59)
      - Argus Book Shop, 1938-1940 (Box 200, Folder 60)
      - L'art ancien S. A., 1923-1931, 1936-1940 (Box 200, Folder 61)
      - Atkinson, Reginald, 1925-1926 (Box 200, Folder 62)
      - B (Box 200, Folder 63)
      - B. H. Blackwell, Ltd., 1922-1928 (Box 201, Folder 64-68)
      - B. Login and Sons, 1925-1942 (Box 201, Folder 69-70)
      - Balliére, Tindal and Cox, 1930-1937 (Box 201, Folder 71)
      - Barnard, P.M., 1923-1924, 1932-1934 (Box 201, Folder 72)
      - Bedford Bookshop, 1932-1936 (Box 201, Folder 73)
      - Benzanson, Stanley O., 1936-1937 (Box 201, Folder 74)
      - Bernard Quaritch Ltd., 1924-1941 (Box 201, Folder 75-77)
      - Bernh, Liebisch, 1926, 1938-1939 (Box 201, Folder 78)
      - Berthel, Albert, 1931 (Box 201, Folder 79)
      - Birrel and Garnett, 1924-1931 (Box 201, Folder 80)
      - Björk and Börjesson, undated (Box 201, Folder 81)
      - Blackiston, P., 1931-1932, 1935, 1949-1950 (Box 201, Folder 82)
      - Bligh, Eric, 1923-1935, 1937-1939 (Box 202, Folder 83-91)
      - Block, Andrew, 1929-1936 (Box 203, Folder 92)
      - Bowes and Bowes, 1926-1936 (Box 203, Folder 93)
      - Brick Row Book Shop, 1933-1937 (Box 203, Folder 94)
      - British Museum catalogue, undated (Box 203, Folder 95)
      - Brown, Frank E., 1935-1937 (Box 203, Folder 96)
      - Brussell, J. R., 1935-1937 (Box 203, Folder 97)
      - Burgersdiik and Neirmans, 1925-1929 (Box 203, Folder 98)
      - C (Box 203, Folder 99)
      - C. A. Stonehill, Inc., 1934-1939 (Box 203, Folder 100)
      - Cambridge University Press, 1929-1931 (Box 203, Folder 101)
      - Cammermeyers Boghandel, 1928-1931 (Box 203, Folder 102)
      - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1932-1954 (Box 203, Folder 103)
      - Cleverdon Bookshop, 1937-1938 (Box 203, Folder 104)
      - Clifton, R. G. [Pine Cupboard Antique Shop], undated (Box 203, Folder 105)
      - Commin, James G., 1925-1929 (Box 203, Folder 106)
      - D (Box 203, Folder 107)
      - Davis and Orioli, 1924-1940, 1942, 1956 (Box 203, Folder 108)
      - Dawson's Book Shop, 1931-1937 (Box 203, Folder 109)
      - Dobell, 1923-1938 (Box 203, Folder 110)
      - E (Box 203, Folder 111)
      - E. P. Goldschmidt and Co., Ltd., 1927-1941, 1956 (Box 204, Folder 112-115)
      - Elkin Mathews, Ltd., 1928-1930, 1940-1958 (Box 204, Folder 116)
      - Elliot, H. K., 1956 (Box 204, Folder 117)
      - F (Box 204, Folder 118)
      - Fibiger, B. R., 1931 (Box 204, Folder 119)
      - Fleming, R. B., 1927-1931 (Box 204, Folder 120)
      - Fletcher, H. M., 1931-1939 (Box 204, Folder 121)
      - Fletcher, J. Kyle, 1930, 1932, 1936-1941 (Box 204, Folder 122)
      - Frampton, R. S., 1925-1938 (Box 204, Folder 123)
      - Friehold, E. G., 1925-1930 (Box 204, Folder 124)
      - G (Box 204, Folder 125)
      - Gardenside Bookshop, 1936-1937 (Box 204, Folder 126)
      - Gibbs, C. J., 1955 (Box 204, Folder 127)
      - Godfrey, Thomas, 1922-1937 (Box 204, Folder 128)
      - Goodspeed's Bookshop, 1927-1940, 1955-1957 (Box 204, Folder 129)
      - Grafton and Co., 1924-1942 (Box 205, Folder 130-132)
      - Grant, John, 1923-1931, 1933-1940 (Box 205, Folder 133)
      - Green Bookshop, 1937-1938 (Box 205, Folder 134)
      - Gregory, George, 1923-1930 (Box 205, Folder 135)
      - Grune and Scratton, 1947-1955 (Box 205, Folder 136)
      - Gunther, R. T., 1923-1931 (Box 205, Folder 137)
      - Guntrip, E., 1926-1931 (Box 205, Folder 138)
      - H (Box 205, Folder 139)
      - H. K. Lewis and Co., 1923-1942, 1953-1954 (Box 205, Folder 140-141)
      - Halliday, Barnard, 1924-1937 (Box 205, Folder 142)
      - Harper, Lathrop C., 1930-1931 (Box 205, Folder 143)
      - Harper and Brothers, 1931, 1946, 1951 (Box 205, Folder 144)
      - Henry and Co., 1932-1936 (Box 205, Folder 145)
      - Henry Schuman Inc. [Publishers]
        See: Series I, box 38, folders 555 See: Series I, box 68, folders 945-951 See: Series I, boxes 156-157, folders 2233-2247
      - Hirschwaldsche Buchhandlung, 1927-1938 (Box 205, Folder 146)
      - Hodgson's, 1923-1930 (Box 206, Folder 147)
      - Hoosier Bookshop, 1934-1937 (Box 206, Folder 148)
      - Howes, C., 1929-1938 (Box 206, Folder 149)
      - Huth, Ch., 1937-1939 (Box 206, Folder 150)
      - International Antiquariaat, 1923-1939 (Box 206, Folder 151)
      - Interscience Publishers Inc., 1947-1950 (Box 206, Folder 152)
      - J (Box 206, Folder 153)
      - J. and J. Leighton, Ltd., 1928-1937 (Box 206, Folder 154)
      - Jefferson Bookshop, 1928-1932 (Box 206, Folder 155)
      - John Bale Sons and Danielsson Ltd., 1929-1935 (Box 206, Folder 156)
      - K (Box 206, Folder 157)
      - Kegan Paul, Trench, Trubner and Co., 1932 (Box 206, Folder 158)
      - Kimpton, Henry, 1923-1938 (Box 206, Folder 159)
      - King, Raphael, 1931-1939 (Box 206, Folder 160)
      - Klemmings, 1931-1932 (Box 206, Folder 161)
      - Koehlers Antiquarium, 1930-1938 (Box 206, Folder 162)
      - L (Box 206, Folder 163)
      - Last, G. H., 1925-1941 (Box 206, Folder 164)
      - Lawson, E. M., 1933-1936, 1956 (Box 206, Folder 165)
      - Lea and Fibiger, 1945-1950 (Box 206, Folder 166)
      - LeFrançois, E., 1926-1939 (Box 206, Folder 167)
      - Levin and Munksgaard, 1932-1936 (Box 206, Folder 168)
      - Librairie Ancienne P. L. Bader, 1930-1940 (Box 206, Folder 169)
      - Librarie E. Droz, 1933-1937 (Box 206, Folder 170)
      - Lorentz, Alfred, 1929-1933 (Box 207, Folder 171)
      - Low, David, 1938-1940 (Box 207, Folder 172)
      - Lubrano, Luigi, 1927-1931 (Box 207, Folder 173)
      - Lyotard, Emile, 1933-1955 (Box 207, Folder 174)
      - M (Box 207, Folder 175)
      - MacPhail, Alexander, 1924-1933 (Box 207, Folder 176)
      - Maggs Brothers, 1923-1942 (Box 207, Folder 177-178)
      - McLeish and Sons, 1925-1940 (Box 207, Folder 179)
      - Meade, Martha L., 1933-1934 (Box 207, Folder 180)
      - Mongenet, J., 1929-1935 (Box 207, Folder 181)
      - Morris, Guido, 1937 (Box 207, Folder 182)
      - Müller, Robert, 1930-1931 (Box 207, Folder 183)
      - Müller, Robert, 1932-1939 (Box 207, Folder 184)
      - Munksgaard, Einar, 1939-1940 (Box 207, Folder 185)
      - Myers and Co., 1923-1938 (Box 207, Folder 186)
      - N (Box 207, Folder 187)
      - Nijhoff's Boekhandel, 1927-1939, 1945 (Box 207, Folder 188)
      - Nonesuch Press, 1930-1931 (Box 207, Folder 189)
      - Norman, F., 1938-1940 (Box 207, Folder 190)
      - Nourry, Emile, 1927-1938 (Box 207, Folder 191)
      - O (Box 207, Folder 192)
      - Old Hickory Bookshop, 1935-1941 (Box 207, Folder 193)
      - Oliver and Boyd, 1930, 1935, 1949 (Box 207, Folder 194)
      - Orr, John, 1929-1932 (Box 207, Folder 195)
      - P (Box 207, Folder 196)
      - Parker and Sons Ltd., 1924-1932 (Box 207, Folder 197)
      - Pickering and Chatto, 1926-1942 (Box 207, Folder 198)
      - Q (Box 207, Folder 199)
      - R (Box 207, Folder 200)
      - R. Lier and Co., 1926-1940 (Box 207, Folder 201-202)
      - Rapport, C. E., 1925-1940, 1956 (Box 208, Folder 203-204)
      - Robinson, Cedric, undated (Box 208, Folder 205)
      - Robinson, William, 1925-1935 (Box 208, Folder 206)
      - Rothacker, O., 1930-1938 (Box 208, Folder 207)
      - S (Box 208, Folder 208)
      - Salamander Bookshop, 1930-1932 (Box 208, Folder 209)
      - Salkeld, John, 1924-1930 (Box 208, Folder 210)
      - Sanders and Co., 1928-1941 (Box 208, Folder 211)
      - Schleiffer, H., 1933-1935 (Box 208, Folder 212)
      - Schuman's
        See: Series I, box 38, folders 555
        See: Series I, box 68, folders 945-951
        See: Series I, box 156-157, 2233-2247
      - Sexton, G., 1927-1941 (Box 208, Folder 213)
      - Shaw, Benjamin D., 1940 (Box 208, Folder 214)
      - Shaw and Sons, 1927-1939 (Box 208, Folder 215)
      - Slatkine, M., 1927-1937 (Box 208, Folder 216)
      - Sotheby and Co., 1925-1940 (Box 208, Folder 217)
      - Sothern and Co., 1923-1941 (Box 208, Folder 218)
      - Stechert and Co., 1926-1937 (Box 208, Folder 219)
      - Steedman, R. P., 1925-1935 (Box 208, Folder 220)
      - Stevens and Brown Ltd., 1929-1935 (Box 208, Folder 221)
      - Suckling and Co., 1925-1942 (Box 208, Folder 222)
      - Sutton, Albert, 1923-1938 (Box 208, Folder 223)
      - Sweet, Forest H., 1958 (Box 208, Folder 224)
      - Swets and Zeitlinger, 1928-1941 (Box 208, Folder 225-226)
      - Symington, J., 1934, 1939-1940 (Box 208, Folder 227)
      - T (Box 208, Folder 228)
      - Taeuber and Weil
        - 1930-1931 (Box 208, Folder 229)
        - 1932-1939 (Box 209, Folder 230)
      - Thorp, Thomas, 1923-1939 (Box 209, Folder 231)
      - Tice and Lynch, Inc., 1940 (Box 209, Folder 232)
      - Tregaskis and Son, 1923-1934 (Box 209, Folder 233)
      - Tuttle, Morehouse and Taylor, 1931-1937 (Box 209, Folder 234)
      - U, V (Box 209, Folder 235)
      - Voynich Estates, 1927-1933 (Box 209, Folder 236)
      - W (Box 209, Folder 237)
      - W. Heffer and Sons Ltd., 1925-1930, 1935-1937, 1950 (Box 209, Folder 238)
      - Webster, D., 1930-1931 (Box 209, Folder 239)
      - Wheldon and Wesley, 1931, 1939-1940 (Box 209, Folder 240)
      - Whitlock's Bookstore, 1930-1938 (Box 209, Folder 241)
      - Williams and Wilkins, 1928-1950, 1958 (Box 209, Folder 242)
      - Wm. Dawson and Sons, 1937-1940 (Box 209, Folder 243)
      - Yale Medical Book Store, 1936-1940, 1945 (Box 209, Folder 244)
      - Year Book Publishers, 1947-1954 (Box 209, Folder 245)
        See also: Series I, box 192, folder 2948
      - Young, Henry, 1936-1940 (Box 209, Folder 246)
      - Z (Box 209, Folder 247)
      - Unidentified (Box 209, Folder 248)
    - Quotations
      - Banks, Joseph, undated (Box 209, Folder 249)
      - Vesalius, Andreas, 1939-1965 (Box 209, Folder 250-251)
  - Bibliotheca Osleriana [notes on its history and dedication]
    See: Series I, box 34, folder 477
  - Boyle, Robert
    - 115. A Bibliography of the Honourable Robert Boyle (1932)
      - Correspondence, undated (Box 210, Folder 252)
      - Mailing lists, undated (Box 210, Folder 253)
      - Notes, undated (Box 210, Folder 254)
      - Reviews, 1932-1933 (Box 210, Folder 255)
    - 151. Addenda to 'A Bibliography of the Honourable Robert Boyle' (1933)
      - Correspondence, A-Z, 1934 (Box 210, Folder 256-257)
      - Typescript, 1933 (Box 210, Folder 258)
    - 515. The Honourable Robert Boyle, F. R.S. (1960), 1953-1959
      - Correspondence, 1953-1960 (Box 210, Folder 259-260)
      - Drafts, 1960 (Box 210, Folder 261-263)
    - 519. A Bibliography of the Honourable Robert Boyle
      - Census of Sceptical Chymyst, 1959 (Box 210, Folder 264)
      - Correspondence
        - A-B, 1954-1960 (Box 210, Folder 265)
        - C, 1954-1959 (Box 211, Folder 266)
        - Clarendon Press, 1959-1960 (Box 211, Folder 267)
        - D-Z, 1941-1960 (Box 211, Folder 268-272)
      - Drafts, ca., 1959 (Box 211, Folder 273-279)
      - Drafts, Circa 1959 (Box 212, Folder 280)
      - Fragments and random pages, Circa 1960 (Box 212, Folder 281)
      - Notes, 1938-1960 (Box 212, Folder 282)
      - Review, undated (Box 212, Folder 283)
    - Booksellers' correspondence, 1923; 1932-1954 (Box 212, Folder 284-286)
    - Duplicates sold, 1940-1942 (Box 212, Folder 287)
    - Portraits and illustrations, 1931-1959, undated (Box 212, Folder 288)
  - Cushing, Harvey
    - 232. A Bibliography of the Writings of Harvey Cushing Prepared on the Occasion of his Seventieth Birthday, April 8, 1939 by the Harvey Cushing Society (1939)
      - Correspondence
        - A-Z, 1938-1939 (Box 212, Folder 289-290)
        - Second edition, 1939-1941, undated (Box 212, Folder 291)
      - Financial, 1939-1940 (Box 212, Folder 292)
      - Reviews, 1939-1940 (Box 212, Folder 293)
    - 337. Harvey Cushing, a Biography (1946)
      - Background
        - Clippings, Circa 1892-1941 (Box 213, Folder 294)
        - Correspondence
          - A-D, Circa 1939-1946 (Box 213, Folder 295-302)
          - E-Ma, Circa1939-1946 (Box 214, Folder 303-316)
            See also: Series I, box 84, folders 1168-1169
          - Me-S, ca., 1939-1946 (Box 215, Folder 317-328)
          - T-Z, ca., 1939-1946 (Box 216, Folder 329-334)
          - Unidentified, Circa 1939-1946 (Box 216, Folder 329-334)
        - Memorabilia, 1887-1945 (Box 216, Folder 335)
        - Notes, 1939-1946 (Box 216, Folder 336)
        - Notices requesting information, 1939 (Box 216, Folder 337)
      - Correspondence, post-publication (Box 216, Folder 338)
        - A-L [bound volume], 1946-1947 (Box 217, Folder 339)
        - M-Z [bound volume], 1946-1947 (Box 217, Folder 340)
        - Additional, 1946-1947 (Box 218, Folder 341)
      - Correspondence with publishers, 1939-1946 (Box 218, Folder 342-343)
      - Design; promotion; reviews, 1945-1946 (Box 218, Folder 344)
        See also: Series VI, box 319, folder 3
      - Drafts, Circa 1945 (Box 218, Folder 345-348)
      - Movie rights, undated (Box 218, Folder 349)
    - Cushing General Hospital: dedication, 1943-1944 (Box 218, Folder 350)
    - Estate, 1939-1943 (Box 219, Folder 351)
    - Funeral, 1939-1946 (Box 219, Folder 352)
    - LePuy Diary, 1943-1947 (Box 219, Folder 353-356)
    - Portrait by Deane Keller for the Hospital del Salvador in Santiago, Chile [correspondence, clippings, and photographs], 1939-1950 (Box 219, Folder 357-361)
    - Radio broadcasts, 1938-1940, 1946, 1948 (Box 220, Folder 362)
    - Seventieth birthday volume
      - Correspondence, 1939-1941 (Box 220, Folder 363-365)
      - Correspondence concerning publication, 1939-1941 (Box 220, Folder 366-367)
      - Drafts, 1939, undated (Box 220, Folder 368)
      - Reviews, 1939-1940 (Box 220, Folder 369)
      - Scrapbook, 1939 (Box 220, Folder 370)
    - Short title catalog, 1943 (Box 220, Folder 371)
    - Tributes, 1939 (Box 220, Folder 372)
  - Garrison, Fielding: Introduction to the History of Medicine
    - Chapter material [includes typescripts, background materials and notes]
      - Preface and introduction, undated (Box 221, Folder 373)
      - Prehistoric science, undated (Box 221, Folder 374)
      - The plague of Athens, undated (Box 221, Folder 375)
      - Egyptian medicine, undated (Box 221, Folder 376)
      - Mesopotamian medicine, undated (Box 221, Folder 377)
      - Egyptian and Mesopotamian medicine, undated (Box 221, Folder 378)
      - Sumerian, Oriental and Hindu medicine, undated (Box 221, Folder 379)
      - Greek and Roman medicine, undated (Box 221, Folder 380)
      - Byzantine medicine, undated (Box 221, Folder 381)
      - Medieval medicine, undated (Box 221, Folder 382)
      - 15th and 16th century medicine, undated (Box 221, Folder 383)
      - 17th century medicine, undated (Box 221, Folder 384)
      - 18th century medicine, undated (Box 221, Folder 385)
      - Modern, undated (Box 222, Folder 386)
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1939-1951 (Box 222, Folder 387-388)
    - W. B. Saunders Co., 1953-1959 (Box 222, Folder 389-390)
    - Design, undated (Box 222, Folder 391)
    - Errata, undated (Box 222, Folder 392)
    - Illustrations, undated (Box 222, Folder 393)
    - Random pages, undated (Box 222, Folder 394)
  - Howell, William: Textbook of Physiology [15th-18th editions]
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1944-1955 (Box 222, Folder 395-398)
      - Barron, D. and Ponder, E., 1951-1954 (Box 222, Folder 399)
        See also: Series I, box 14, folder 201
      - Biggs, Rosemary, 1953-1955 (Box 222, Folder 400)
      - Blake, William D., 1953-1954 (Box 222, Folder 401)
        See also: Series I, box 20, folder 277
      - Brobeck, J. R., 1944-1955 (Box 222, Folder 402)
        See also: Series I, box 23, folder 326
      - Clarke, Robert W., 1944-1953 (Box 223, Folder 403)
        See also: Series I, box 36, folders 528-529
      - Cowgill, George, 1944-1953 (Box 223, Folder 404)
      - Elkinton, J., 1944-1953 (Box 223, Folder 405)
      - Fenton, P. F., 1951-1953 (Box 223, Folder 406)
      - Ferguson, John H., 1944-1948, 1953 (Box 223, Folder 407-408)
        See also: Series I, box 51, folders 751-752
      - Forbes, Thomas R., 1953-1955 (Box 223, Folder 409)
        See also: Series I, box 53, folders 787-788
      - Gardner, William U., 1944-1946, 1950-1955 (Box 223, Folder 410)
        See also: Series I, box 67, folder 934
      - Gelfan, Samuel, 1952-1955 (Box 223, Folder 411)
        See also: Series I, box 67, folders 939-940
      - Grenell, Robert G., 1948, 1954 (Box 223, Folder 412)
        See also: Series I, box 72, folder 1008
      - Hamilton, W. G., 1944-1946, 1949 (Box 223, Folder 413)
      - Hernández-Peón, R., 1953-1955 (Box 223, Folder 414)
      - Hitchcock, David I., 1944-1955 (Box 223, Folder 415)
        See also: Series I, box 82, folder 1146
      - Hoff, Ebbe Curtis, 1944-1946, 1951-1954 (Box 223, Folder 416)
        See also: Series I, boxes 82-83, folders 1153-1158
      - Hoff, Hebbel E., 1944-1949, 1952-1955 (Box 223, Folder 417-418)
        See also: Series I, box 83, folders 1159-1163
      - Hooker, Charles W., 1944-1946, 1953-1955 (Box 223, Folder 419)
      - Howell, William H., 1944-1946 (Box 223, Folder 420)
        See also: Series I, box 85, folder 1181
      - Lamport, Harold, 1944-1954 (Box 223, Folder 421)
        See also: Series I, box 105, folders 1436-1438
      - Landauer, W., 1944-1945, 1950 (Box 223, Folder 422)
      - Livingston, Robert B., 1949-1955 (Box 223, Folder 423)
        See also: Series I, boxes 110-111, folders 1522-1527
      - Lloyd, David P. C., 1947-1955 (Box 223, Folder 424)
        See also: Series I, box 110, folder 1511
      - Nachmansohn, D., 1953-1955 (Box 223, Folder 425)
        See also: Series I, box 130, folder 1769
      - Nims, L. F., 1944-1954 (Box 223, Folder 426)
        See also: Series I, box 133, folder 1808
      - Patterson, John L.
        See: box 223, Folder 416
      - Patton, Harry, 1944-1948 (Box 223, Folder 427)
        See also: Series I, box 140, folder 1896
      - Pitts, Robert, 1944-1948 (Box 223, Folder 428)
        See also: Series I, box 143, folder 1943
      - Ponder, Eric, 1944-1947 (Box 223, Folder 429)
      - Ruch, Theodore, 1944-1960 (Box 223, Folder 430-431)
        See also: Series I, box 152, folders 2075-2079
      - Russell, J. A., 1953-1954 (Box 223, Folder 432)
      - W. B. Saunders Co., 1942-1960 (Box 224, Folder 433-441)
        See also: Series I, box 175, folders 2614-2615
      - Weymouth, W. F., 1944-1948 (Box 224, Folder 442)
      - Wilhelmi, Alfred, 1944-1954 (Box 224, Folder 443)
      - Wright, Helen P., 1953-1955 (Box 224, Folder 444)
    - Drafts
      - 15th edition
        - Prospectus of revision, 1944 (Box 224, Folder 445)
        - Preface, 1945 (Box 224, Folder 446)
        - Historical introduction, 1945 (Box 225, Folder 447)
        - Chapters 11-15, n.d. (Box 225, Folder 448-452)
      - 16th edition: chapters 7-9, undated (Box 225, Folder 453-455)
    - Editors' meetings [minutes and memoranda] (Box 225, Folder 456)
    - Financial, 1944-1961 (Box 225, Folder 457-458)
    - Requests for permission to publish, 1944-1945, 1950, 1954 (Box 225, Folder 459-460)
    - Reviews, 1946-1955 (Box 225, Folder 461-462)